A Guide to the Thomas Overton Moss papers, 1891-1939
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Thomas Overton Moss papers, 1891-1939
The Library of Virginia
45245
.45 cu. ft. and 1 box
Thomas Overton Moss
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Crown Collectibles, Chesterfield, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Thomas Overton Moss was born 13 October 1893 in Hanover County, Virginia, to Thomas Overton Moss (b. 1839) and Nina Wood Moss (1857-1930). He attended Hampden-Sydney College and received his law degree from T.C. Williams School of Law at the University of Richmond. Moss moved to Richmond, Virginia, where he began practicing law. He also became active in local and state politics. Moss married Virginia Johnson in 1919 and they divorced ca. 1931. His second wife was named Louise. Moss married a third time on 9 August 1937 to Doris Braur Mann of Washington D.C., and they had an adopted daughter. Moss died 23 June 1939 in Richmond, and was buried in Hollywood Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1891-1939, of Thomas Overton Moss (1893-1939) of Richmond, Virginia, consisting of accounts, agreements, contracts, deeds, insurance policies, letters, plats, receipts, and other papers concering his activities as a practicing lawyer, his involvement in state politics, and his activities in real estate and business, as well as regarding his homes, especially the construction of his house in Windsor Farms.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I: Correspondence, 1925-1939
II: Real property, 1891-1938
III: Old Dominion Mortgage Corporation, 1928-1934
IV: Insurance, 1907-1933
V: Accounts and Receipts.
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1925-1939., Extent: 8 folders. (Folder 1-8)
  - Correspondence, 1925-1927. (Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1928. (Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1929. (Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1930. (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1933. (Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1934-1936. (Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1937. (Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939. (Folder 8)
- Series II: Real Property, 1891-1938., Extent: 6 folders. (Folder 9-14)
  - Real property: Hampton Gardens home (Roslyn Road and Harlan Circle) plat, 1926-1927. (Folder 9)
  - Real property: Windsor Farms home--Windsor Farms, Inc., 1938. (Folder 10)
  - Real property: Windsor Farms home--Joseph F. Black, general contractor. (Folder 11)
  - Real property: Windsor Farms home--Laburnum Realty Corporation. (Folder 12)
  - Real property: Windsor Farms home, plat, 24 November 1937. (Folder 13)
  - Real property: Hanover County, Virginia, 1891-1908. (Folder 14)
- Series III: Old Dominion Mortgage Corporation, 1928-1934., Extent: 1 folder. (Folder 15)
- Series IV: Insurance policies, 1907-1933., Extent: 1 folder. (Folder 16)
- Series V: Accounts and Receipts., Extent: 6 folders. (Folder 17-22)
  - Accounts and receipts: automobile. (Folder 17)
  - Accounts and receipts: clothing and accessories. (Folder 18)
  - Accounts and receipts: florists. (Folder 19)
  - Accounts and receipts: Home furnishings/repairs. (Folder 20)
  - Accounts and receipts: newspapers. (Folder 21)
  - Accounts and receipts: miscellaneous--American Legion, cameras, country club, dairies, nurseries, medical, printing, stationery and office supplies, telephones, and theater. (Folder 22)